Hale Family Papers, 1787-1988
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
- Photographs and Visual Images
  - Places
    - Matunuck, RI
      - Robert Beverly Hale Memorial Library: photographs, 1967 (Box 120, Folder 29)
    - 1748 N St., Washington, DC: photograph, undated (Box 120, Folder 30)
    - Nathan Hale House, Coventry, CT: photographs, postcard, 1920-21 (Box 120, Folder 31)
    - Nathan Hale School, New London, CT: postcard, undated (Box 120, Folder 32)
    - "Oak Knoll," Danvers, MA: photograph, undated (Box 120, Folder 33)
    - "Octorara House," Rowlandsville, MD (home of Camilla (Conner) Hale: photograph, undated (Box 120, Folder 34)
    - "Sandy Down," 213 Highland St., Dedham, MA (home of Philip Leslie and Lilian (Westcott) Hale)
      - Photographs of house, 1910s-20s (Box 120, Folder 35)
      - Photographs of garden, 1910s-40s (Box 120, Folder 36)
      - Photographs of garden with painters' models, 1920s (Box 121, Folder 1)
      - Photographs of environs, 1920s (Box 121, Folder 2)
    - South Congregational Church, Boston, MA (parish of Edward Everett Hale): photograph, undated (Box 121, Folder 3)
    - Studio of Philip Leslie Hale, The Fenway, Boston, MA: photographs, undated (Box 121, Folder 4)
  - Subjects
    - Arthur Hale's boat "The Teal": photographs, 1918-19 (Box 121, Folder 5)
    - Civil War photographs, art, 1860s (Box 121, Folder 6)
    - Lincoln Memorial statue by Adolph Alexander Weinman, Hodgenville, KY: photographs, 1909 (Box 121, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified, undated (Box 121, Folder 8)
  - Daguerreotypes, tintypes, and cased images
    - Everett, Edward: daguerreotype (Box 122)
    - Everett, John: miniature painted portrait done in Lexington, MA (poor condition), 1820 (Box 122)
    - Hale, Charles: tintype, circa 1860s and 4 daguerreotypes, circa 1856 (Box 122)
    - Hale, Edward Everett: 3 daguerreotypes, circa 1840s (Box 123)
    - Hale, Ellen Day: daguerreotype, circa 1858 (Box 123)
    - Hale, Lucretia Peabody: 2 daguerreotypes, circa 1850s (Box 123)
    - Hale, Nathan, Jr.: daguerreotypes, circa 1860s (Box 123)
    - Hale, Sarah Everett: daguerreotype of drawing (Box 123)
    - Group daguerreotypes
      - Hale, Susan and Sarah Preston (Everett), circa 1840? (Box 123)
      - Hale, Emily (Perkins) and Ellen Day, circa 1855 (Box 124)
      - Hale, Charles Alexander and Arthur, circa 1865 (Box 124)
      - Hale, Susan and Edward Everett Hale, circa 1850 (Box 124)
      - Hale, Charles, Susan, and two unidentified women, circa 1850 (Box 124)
    - Westcott, Harriet (Clarke)
      - Daguerreotype, circa 1852 (Box 124)
      - Daguerreotype with her father, circa 1852-53 (Box 124)
    - Unidentified daguerreotypes: 2 poses unidentified woman; unidentified woman; unidentified child (Box 124)
    - 4 glass paperweights with photographs of Charles Hale, circa 1860s (Box 125)
    - 2 ceramic? tiles with photographs of Nathan Hale, Jr., undated (Box 125)
    - Ceramic? tile with photograph of Charles Alexander Hale and Arthur Hale, undated (Box 125)
  - Photograph albums
    - Beecher, Perkins, Peabody, Stowe, Gilman, White, Whitney, circa 1860s (Box 126)
    - Hale, Edward Everett with Helen and Ethel Freeman: circa 1900 (Box 126)
    - Hale, Edward Everett in the White Mountains with the Freemans, circa 1900 (Box 126)
    - Unidentified, circa 1850s-60s [includes lobster man] (Box 127)
    - Hale, Robert Beverly: tintype album, circa 1890 (Box 127)
    - Hale, Charles, 1866 (Box 127)
    - Hale, Charles?, 1860s, circa 1872 (Box 127)
- Oversize Materials
  - General
    - Hale, Ellen Day: address book, n.d.; bible, gift of Lyman Beecher, n.d.; financial record; calling lists, 1904, 1908 (Box 128)
    - Everett Family: Everett, Alexander Hill: passport, 1822; royalty statements, 1847; Everett, John: passport, 1822; Everett, Oliver: Humane Society membership certificate, 1791 (Box 129, Folder 1)
    - Hale, Alexander: Harvard diploma, 1848; certificate for completion of Greek requirements, Harvard, 1848 (Box 129, Folder 2)
    - Hale, Charles: Harvard diploma, 1850 (Box 129, Folder 3)
    - Hale, Edward Everett and Emily (Perkins) household: New Year's gift chart, late 1860s or early 1870s (Box 129, Folder 4)
    - Hale, Edward Everett: Harvard diploma, 1879; flyer "A Mutual Bank of Circulation and Discount," undated; seating chart, Commercial Club of Boston dinner, 5 Oct 1889 "complimentary to delegates to the Congress of American Nations"; Report on Antioch College, n.d.; "An Outside and Inside View of Humboldt College," undated; plot plan of the "old church estate," 1801; certificate of honorary membership, Kansas State Historical Society, 1899; Commonwealth of Massachusetts governor's proclamation establishing Thanksgiving Day, 1860 (Box 129, Folder 5)
    - Hale, Ellen Day: diploma of merit, North, Central, and South American Exposition, New Orleans, 1885-86; tracing by Gabrielle Clements of plot plan of properties at Folly Cove, 1906; 1916 copy of 1801 plant of Folly Hill pasture (Box 129, Folder 6)
    - Hale, Herbert Dudley: Ecole des Beaux Art, Section d'Architecture, instruction for Concours d'emulation du 4 Mar 1891 (Box 129, Folder 7)
    - Hale, Nathan, Jr.: Harvard diploma, 1838; army commissions and resignation, 1844-49 (Box 129, Folder 8)
    - Hale, Nathan, Sr.
      - Biographical: Williams College diploma (Box 129, Folder 9)
      - Activities
        - Miscellaneous: American Rail Road Journal, 3 Sep 1836; bill of Mortality City of Boston, 1846; certificate of membership, Massachusetts Society for Promoting Agriculture, 1818 (Box 129, Folder 10)
        - Boston and Worcester Rail Road (Box 129, Folder 11)
        - Boston Water Commission (Box 129, Folder 12)
        - Improved Stereotype Plate (Box 129, Folder 13)
    - Hale, Robert Beverly: 2 publications record charts, undated (Box 129, Folder 14)
    - Hale, Susan: passport, 1867 (Box 129, Folder 15)
    - Newspapers: J Russell's Gazette, 30 Jan 1800; Boston Gazette, 30 Jun 1806; Boston Daily Evening Transcript, 26 Jul 1838; Massachusetts Centinel, 10 Nov 1787; Independent Chronicle and Boston Patriot, 8 Jul 1835 (Box 129, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous: map of Boston "from actual survey" by Osgood Carleton, 1796; 12 Jul 1848 letter James Brown (for the holders of Pennsylvania stock resident in England) to Governor David R. Porter of Pennsylvania; Japanese print [woman in kimono with peonies and apple blossoms], undated; reprint of The Boston News-Letter "first newspaper ever published in America," 1893 Historical Publishing Co. (Box 129, Folder 17)
  - Artwork
    - Hale, Ellen Day: sketchbooks (7), 1873?, 1879, 1907?, undated (Box 130)
    - Hale, Philip Leslie: sketchbooks (2), undated (Box 131)
    - Hale, Lilian (Westcott)
      - Sketchbooks (8), undated (Box 131)
      - Printing plates: "Spring Reverie," "Portrait of Miss Margaret Williams" (Box 132)
    - Hale, Philip Leslie: printing plates: "A Family Affair," "Cap'n Peter Turner," "Woman with Fan," "La Donna Mi-Velata" (Box 132)
    - Hale, Susan: 11 watercolors, ( "Saratoga, March 11, 1880" (still life with mantelpiece and calla lilies); "Magnolia, 1879(?)" (seaside landscape); landscape with trees and stone walls, undated; river landscape, undated; 2 views of hillside with castle-like building (on 1 piece of paper), undated; view into a conservatory, undated; town scene, probably Egypt or Palestine, undated; city scenes, Europe?; two boots and the tip of an umbrella, undated; mountain scene, undated; landscape, undated) (Box 133, Folder 1)
    - Hale, Ellen Day
      - Etchings ("First Night in Venice," undated; "Father Damien" (7), 1889) (Box 133, Folder 2)
      - Photographs of art (Box 133, Folder 3)
    - Clements, Gabrielle: etchings ("Hills of Nazareth," "Mt. Etna, Taormina," "Porte del Garde, Azores," "Bell Tower, Taormina"), undated (Box 133, Folder 4)
    - Nordhoff, Evelyn: etchings ("House at Coronado," "Santa Barbara") (Box 133, Folder 5)
    - Hale, Lilian (Westcott): sketches, miscellaneous art, 1886-97, undated (Box 134, Folder 1-6)
    - Hale, Philip Leslie: drawings, etchings, miscellaneous art, oil sketch of Edward Everett Hale on wood panel, undated (Box 134, Folder 7-13)
    - Hale, Ellen Day
      - Drawings: bull, head of a man, seated man, head of a man (Box 135, Folder 1)
      - Oil study: portrait of a man (same as seated man above) (Box 135, Folder 2)
    - Hale, Susan: 2 oils: woman sitting on a porch, nude man on a stool, undated (Box 135, Folder 3)
  - Photographs and Visual Images
    - Beecher Family: poster of Henry Ward Beecher "from the painting by T. Hicks," published 1853; poster map of Nook Farm as it was circa 1855, published 1970s? (Box 135, Folder 4)
    - Hale, Edward Everett and Emily (Perkins): EEH in an unidentified group, undated; 2 photographs of EEH; 2 copies photograph with Edward Cummings; EPH blow up of photograph, undated (Box 135, Folder 5)
    - Hale, Robert Beverly: 3 photographs as a child (Box 135, Folder 6)
    - Hale, Sarah Everett: drawing, probably by William Witmore Story, circa 1840 [broken] (Box 135, Folder 7)
    - South Congregational Church: 2 engravings: architect's renderings of interior by Nathaniel J. Bradlee, undated (Box 135, Folder 8)
    - Hale, Edward Everett: plaster cast of a bas relief by W. Clark Noble, 1909 (Box 136, Folder 1)
    - Beecher, Henry Ward: photograph, undated; Beecher, Lyman: pencil drawing, undated (Box 136, Folder 2)
    - Everett, Edward: lithograph, 1854 (Box 136, Folder 3)
    - Hale, Lilian (Westcott): wedding photograph, 1902; Hale, Philip Leslie: etching of PLH? while painting by William Meyerowitz, 1920; Westcott, Harriet (Clarke): photo as a child, circa 1852 (Box 136, Folder 4)
    - [Hansell], Harriet Ann and Hale, Nancy: photograph, circa 1914 (Box 136, Folder 5)
    - Hale, Philip Leslie in art class, France?, undated: photograph, circa 1914; Sullivan, Mary, model for Boston artists, 2 photos, undated (Box 136, Folder 6)
    - Hale, Robert Beverly: Glee club photograph, undated; portrait photograph in frame with pansy embroidery (Box 136, Folder 7)
    - Hale, Edward Everett: portrait photograph, 2 copies, 1860s? (Box 136, Folder 8)
- Artifacts
  - Medal, Schola Latinae Bostoniensis, awarded to Nathan Hale [Jr] for a translation from Caesar, 1830 (Box 137, Folder 1)
  - Medal, Schola Latinae Bostoniensis, Edward E. Hale Industria praimuim, 1832 (Box 137, Folder 2)
  - Hale, Sarah Everett, a prize for most amiable, Miss Susan Whitney's School, circa 1820s (Box 137, Folder 3)
  - Boston Public Latin School
    - Award to Alexander Hale for Industry, 1841 (Box 137, Folder 4)
    - Award to Alexander Hale for Industry, 1842 (Box 137, Folder 5)
    - Award to Alexander Hale for a Latin Narrative, 1844 (Box 137, Folder 6)
    - Award to Alexander Hale for Exemplary Conduct, 1844 (Box 137, Folder 7)
    - Reward of Merit by the School Committee to A. Hale, 1844 (Box 137, Folder 8)
  - Phi Beta Kappa fob?, key?
    - Edward Everett Hale, undated (Box 137, Folder 9)
    - Charles Hale, undated (Box 137, Folder 10)
    - Nathan Hale, Jr., undated (Box 137, Folder 11)
  - Hale, Charles: studs? cuff links?, undated (Box 137, Folder 12a-b)
  - Hale, Edward Everett: ring, inscribed "EEH from J(?)EH Mass Ga S.C." (Box 137, Folder 13)
  - Hale, Charles: napkin ring inscribed "Charles" (Box 137, Folder 14)
  - "Hair" pin inscribed "Papa Aug 16 1784 Feb 8 1863, Mama Sept 5 1795 Nov 14 1866 (Box 137, Folder 15)
  - Snuff? box decorated with a face with tongue sticking out (Box 137, Folder 16)
  - Cigarette? case "PLH" (Box 137, Folder 17)
  - Egyptian? artifacts
    - Metal item, looks like a small pitcher (Box 137, Folder 18)
    - Stone? cylinder (Box 137, Folder 19)
    - Stone? cylinder (Box 137, Folder 20)
    - Metal item with ram head (Box 137, Folder 21)
    - Clay lamps(?) (6) (Box 138, Folder 22-27)
    - Carved tusk or bone (Box 138, Folder 28)
    - Stone with something carved on it (Box 139, Folder 29)
    - Box of small scarabs (6) and small human figure (Box 140, Folder 30)
    - Sarcophagus box, metal (Box 140, Folder 31)
    - Carved crocodile, black (Box 140, Folder 32)
    - Carved crocodile, brown with broken nose (Box 140, Folder 33)
    - Metal figure (Box 140, Folder 34)
    - Metal head of bird with long beak (Box 140, Folder 35)
    - Carving of human figure standing on two crocodiles (Box 140, Folder 36)
  - Pair of spectacles (Box 141, Folder 37)
  - Pair of sunglasses (Box 141, Folder 38)
  - Pair of folding sunglasses for travel in leather case (Box 141, Folder 39)
  - Flatware (knife, fork, spoon) set for travel, possibly used at Harvard (Box 141, Folder 40)
  - Centigrade thermometer in case (Box 141, Folder 41)
  - Sewing kit for travel (Box 141, Folder 42)
  - Leather purse with painted glass bottle inside (Box 141, Folder 43)
  - Richard Milton Award to Lilian Westcott Hale, 16th annual exhibition of paintings by contemporary artists of New England, 1945 (Box 141, Folder 44)
  - Concord Art Association, 9th Annual Exhibition award of honor: plaque, 1925 (Box 141, Folder 45)
  - Concord Art Association Medal of Honor, Lilian W. Hale, undated (Box 141, Folder 46)
  - Cup and ribbon, Albermarle Art Association Jury Show (Lilian Westcott Hale?), 1959 (Box 142, Folder 47)
  - 2 Child's underwaists (Box 142, Folder 48-49)
  - Painted wooden box (Box 143, Folder 50)
  - Hat worn by Edward Everett Hale (Box 143, Folder 51)
    [Donated to Pettaquamscutt Historical Society, July 2007]